<?xml version="1.0"?>
<pxyservd>
  
  <server>
    <name>ceres.irc-hispano.org</name>
    <id>P1</id>
    <numeric>4032</numeric>
    <maxclients>1</maxclients>
    <info>IRC-Hispano Proxy Scanner</info>
    <sendq>1000000</sendq>
  </server>
  
  <!-- MODIFICAR ESTO -->
  <hub>
    <address>172.16.0.1</address>
    <port>4400</port>
    <bind-address></bind-address>
    <password>duck</password>
  </hub>
  
  <client>
    <nickname>pxyh-ceres</nickname>
    <nick-change-delay></nick-change-delay>
    <username>proxyscan</username>
    <hostname>bots.irc-hispano.org</hostname>
    <realname>IRC-Hispano Proxy Scanner</realname>
    <userip>0.0.0.0</userip>
    <usermode>+idkoBrh</usermode>
    <channel>#proxy_info</channel>
    <channel-mode>+tnis</channel-mode>
    <channel-timestamp>1004078035</channel-timestamp>
    <show-cached>1</show-cached>
  </client>
  
  <noscan>
    <server>sol.irc-hispano.org</server>
    <server>deep.space</server>
    <server>soyuz.irc-hispano.org</server>
    <server>vulcan.irc-hispano.org</server>
    <server>viento.irc-hispano.org</server>
    <server>viento2.irc-hispano.org</server>
    <userip>127.0.0.1</userip>
    <userip>255.255.255.255</userip>
    <userip>0/8</userip>
    <userip>10/8</userip>
    <userip>172.16/12</userip>
    <userip>192.168/16</userip>
    <!-- AGREGAR IPS de bots, admins,... -->
  </noscan>
  
  <!-- MODIFICAR ESTO -->
  <scanner>
    <address>172.16.0.5</address>
    <port>9601</port>
    <bind-address></bind-address>
  </scanner>
  
  <log>
    <file type="current">logs/proxy-current.log</file>
    <file type="daily">logs/proxy-yesterday.log</file>
    <file type="system">logs/system.log</file>
    <file type="glines">logs/glines.log</file>
    <file type="opercmds">logs/opercmds.log</file>
    <file type="proxytop">logs/proxytop.db</file>
    <history-dirpath>logs/history</history-dirpath>
    <timezone>GMT</timezone>
  </log>
  
  <gline>
    <delay>900</delay>
    <!-- type constants taken from the OPAS library -->
    <reason type="1">Misconfigured Wingate. Please visit http://www.undernet.org/proxyscan.php </reason><!-- space at the end for mIRC users -->
    <reason type="2">Misconfigured Socks Server. Please visit http://www.undernet.org/proxyscan.php </reason>
    <reason type="3">Misconfigured Socks Server. Please visit http://www.undernet.org/proxyscan.php </reason>
    <reason type="4">Misconfigured Proxy Server. Please visit http://www.undernet.org/proxyscan.php </reason>
    <reason type="0">Misconfigured Proxy Server. Please visit http://www.undernet.org/proxyscan.php </reason>
  </gline>
  
  <notice>
    <line>Esta red tiene en funcionamiento un detector que comprueba</line>
    <line>proxies abiertos, socks/wingates abiertos y troyanos abiertos.</line>
    <line>Si te aparece una conexion desde scan.irc-hispano.org/194.149.73.250</line>
    <line>por favor no la tenga en cuenta, ya que es el detector en accion y NO es un intento hostil.</line>
  </notice>
  
  <help-menu>
IRC-Hispano Proxy Scanner Service Help Menu
===========================================
  Comandos (Solo OPERadores de la red)
  ------------------------------------
    INV             - Te invita al canal de consola
    SERVERS [...]   - Muestra estadisticas de servidores
    STATUS [...]    - Estadisticas del servidor y del demonio de Escaneo
    NOSCAN          - Visualiza la configuracion de NOSCAN
    PROXYTOP        - Proxies encontrados por servidor
    STATS           - Estadisticas Tecnicas
    PXSTATS         - Etatistiicas del demonio de Escaneo
    GREM &lt;GLINE&gt;    - Elimina una Gline puesta por mi
    INFO <nick>     - Muestra informacion del usuario
    INFO <canal>    - Muestra informacion de todos los usuarios del canal
    RECHECK <nick>  - Reescanea a un usuario
    RECHECK <canal> - Reescanea a todos los usuarios de un canal
    HELP CREDITS    - Creditos del bot
    HELP &lt;COMMAND&gt;  - Mas ayuda para el comando &lt;COMMAND&gt;
  </help-menu>
  
  <help topic="inv">
INV
===
  This command gives any global IRC operator an invite on my
  current console channel.
  </help>
  
  <help topic="servers">
SERVERS [-info] [-noscan]
==============================================
Show IRC network tree with optional info:
  -info : Display user count
  -scan : Show scanned servers in bold
  </help>
  
  <help topic="status">
STATUS [-serv|-scan]                     (1/3)
==============================================
General and probably the more interesting command provided by
pxyservd. Call it how often you want to quickly check how pxys
is working.
 
IRC server status
-----------------
A first part displays the IRC server status: number of servers
on the network, number of clients and channels, classical.
pxyservd retrieves the IPs of the network's clients and sends
them to pxyscand, the associated scanner daemon process, for
proxy scanning. "Scan ClientQ" is the number of clients that
haven't been confirmed yet, pxyservd is waiting for a positive
or negative reply from the scanner daemon. Take a look at this
value as it shouldn't grow too much in normal conditions, and
drop as soon as possible otherwise. Note it's normal to always
have some clients in the scan queue... the scanner daemon can't
always reply quickly.
"Unscannable clients" shows the current number of *connected*
clients concerned by a failed scan. A failed scan occurs when
the host or network of this client is unreachable from the proxy
scanner daemon. It is followed by the server's uptime (pxyservd
uptime).
 
Please consult HELP STATUS 2 for detailed description of the
scanner status part.
  </help>

  <help topic="status 2">
STATUS [-serv|-scan]                     (2/3)
==============================================
Scanner status
--------------
First, you need to know that the scanner daemon (pxyscand) is
now separated from the IRC(u) service server (pxyservd).
However, they are able to communicate: first to request proxy
scanning, but for status/stats purposes too. So you may notice
a delay before receiving the scanner status reply if the scanner
daemon is not running locally, for example.
The first lines display status info about the connection between
the server and the scanner daemon. If they are not connected
(eg. the scanner daemon is down), you will see a warning there.
"Scanning activity" is a good indicator about the load of the
scanner daemon. 100%% means all socket slots are taken and it's
doing its best to scan them. Lower values means the scanner
could handle more clients at this time. This percentage is
followed by more precise values: the number of unique IPs
currently being scanned, and the number of scans being performed
at this time. Usually, you have several scans for one IP. The
number of scan is in fact the number of sockets needed to
perform the scans for these IPs (although it's not exactly the
number of open sockets, but more, as some of them might not be
created yet or already closed).
"IP scans completed" is a simple real IP scan counter for the
current session (all sessions in parenthesis). To consult the
scanner's cache hits counter, please use the PXSTATS command.
An average value of scan performed is given too.
 
Please use HELP STATUS 3 for next page.
  </help>
  
  <help topic="status 3">
STATUS [-serv|-scan]                     (3/3)
==============================================
When "ScanQ size" is not zero, the current scanning activity
should be 100%% (the maximum) and you know the scanner can't
process all IPs at the same time: it then adds the IP scan
requests in a queue for later processing. This number should
drop until 0, otherwise you have a little problem.
"Target" is the current selected needed target IP for some
scans (as for Socks 4 discovery). It should be set to an IP of
one of your network's stable IRC server.
"Scan connect() timeout" indicates the number of seconds to
wait before a scan bails out.
 
Following the total number of proxy found, you will find there
the uptime of the scanner daemon. The last part of the STATUS
command shows a detailed table with proxy found counters since
the scanner daemon is launched. For information, additional
"open" counters are provided that count established connections.
 
Options:
        -serv : only displays IRC server status
        -scan : only displays proxy scanner daemon status
  </help>

  <help topic="noscan">
NOSCAN
==============================================
Show pxyservd's "noscan" rules. pxyservd, the IRC(u) service
server part of pxys v2, is configured with a list of IP blocks
that are ignored. Clients using one of these IPs are tagged as
"scanning disabled". Additonally, a list of remote server names
can be provided: clients using these servers are ignored too,
thus useful for services, hubs, or IRC operator only servers.
  </help>

  <help topic="proxytop">
PROXYTOP
==============================================
This command shows the top list of servers where proxy were
found on them (and then G-lined!). It might help you to find
very-open servers with possibly bad I/K-lines rules, or servers
floodbots like... Don't forget to relativize using the provided
MAXUSERS indicator, as big servers obviously have more chance to
host proxied clients.
  </help>
  
  <help topic="stats">
STATS
==============================================
Display statistics about sockets, internal structures and
memory's consumption.
  </help>

  <help topic="pxstats">
PXSTATS
==============================================
Query the proxy scanner daemon for internal statistics. Only
available when pxyscand is connected. Along other obscure
values, it shows the IP cache hits count of already scanned
users. This cache allows the scanner to work in very hard
conditions, avoiding the re-scan of recently checked IPs.
  </help>

  <help topic="grem">
GREM &lt;IP|GLINE&gt;
==============================================
G-line removal method (only for proxyscan G-lines). Please
provide the IP or the banned user@host mask, ie. *@&lt;IP&gt;.
After the remgline, the IP is not ignored, it will be re-scanned
if seen again.
  </help>

  <help topic="info">
INFO &lt;NICK|CHANNEL&gt;
==============================================
Info command about a client or a channel. Its purpose is to give
some proxyscan-related info about a client or channel's clients.
 
Examples:
        INFO bot-42
        INFO #floodland
  </help>
  
  <help topic="recheck">
RECHECK &lt;NICK|CHANNEL&gt;
==============================================
Like GREM, this command performs an action and its purpose is
not only informative, please use with care.
The RECHECK command allows a global IRC operator to ask for a
recheck of a specified user or all users on a given channel.
 
Please note, however, that users matching NOSCAN rules are never
proxy-checked. Also, if the user has not be scanned yet (eg.
he's just connected), this command does nothing. Don't hesitate
to use previously the INFO command on the user or channel if
needed.
 
Note that a notice is sent to my console channel for recheck of
a whole channel.
 
Examples:
        RECHECK bot-42
        RECHECK #floodland
  </help>
  
  <help topic="evreg">
EVREG &lt;MODES&gt;
=============
  This command allows global IRC operators to register for specific
  events. Several modes are provided, each character identifying an
  event. Opers who have event X enabled will be notified by the
  proxyscanner's virtual client (me) when event X occurs.
  
  MODES
  -----
    'p' : new insecure proxy found, show it
    'c' : show proxy-cache hits
    'o' : show global IRC operators using /oper
    'x' : pxyscand connection related events
  
  For example, an oper who want to be notified when a new proxy has
  been found and for /oper's would type: /msg &lt;me&gt; evreg +po
  
  To disable /oper's notifications only: /msg &lt;me&gt; evreg -o
  
  NOTE: Your modes remain until you disconnect or a split between
        you and the proxyscanner occurs.
  </help>
  
  <help topic="credits">
pxyservd v2 - part of pxys v2 software suite
============================================
See: http://pxys.sf.net

Adaptado para IRC-Hispano por
  Toni Garcia   zoltan    <zoltan@irc-dev.net>

Traducido al castellano por
  Toni Garcia   zoltan    <zoltan@irc-dev.net>
  Vacante
  </help>
  
</pxyservd>
